<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sharpstone Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sharpstone Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:14:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Model Thinker by Scott Page, a Book Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/model-thinker-scott-page-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:14:48 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/model-thinker-scott-page-book-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/model_thinker_review.png&#34; alt=&#34;Model Thinker image by ChatGPT&#34; title=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-book-overview&#34;&gt;📖 Book Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt;  The Model Thinker: What you need to know to make data work for you&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt;  Scott E. Page&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published:&lt;/strong&gt;  2021 (expanded edition)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genre/Focus:&lt;/strong&gt;  Popular Science&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-i-read-this&#34;&gt;🧠 Why I Read This&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of my ongoing Doctoral research into Business, Accounting, and Artificial Intelligence, I sought out this book to deepen my understanding of model-driven thinking—a critical skill for modern leadership. Data models are the often-hidden underpinnings of the Information Age, and much of what people refer to as &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; today is actually fast, layered modeling. My goal was to sharpen my ability to interpret, apply, and challenge models effectively. The Model Thinker delivered valuable tools that I am already applying in strategic decision frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Unpacked: Beyond the buzzwords</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-unpacked-beyond-the-buzzwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-unpacked-beyond-the-buzzwords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ai-unpacked-beyond-the-buzzwords&#34;&gt;AI Unpacked: Beyond the buzzwords&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI, AI everywhere, and not a second to think.&lt;/strong&gt; Just like the poor sailors in Coleridge’s The Rime of the Ancient Mariner—surrounded by water but dying of thirst—we’re inundated with AI yet terribly &lt;strong&gt;tempted to implement&lt;/strong&gt; it without pausing to &lt;strong&gt;consider ROI, data readiness, or ethical implications&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’ve been awake at any point since late 2022, you’ve probably been urged to join the AI revolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the Right AI Model: A Practical Comparison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-models-compared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-models-compared/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/AI-Models.png&#34; alt=&#34;AI Models image by ChatGPT&#34; title=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Simon Sinek says &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Start with why&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.  When you know the why you are wanting to use the AI model the other questions and answers can follow relatively easy. Current AI as sophisticated as it may be - is still what is known as &amp;rsquo;narrow&amp;rsquo; this means they are built for specific tasks and contexts. These specific tasks and contexts may be expansive but the range of the expertise is relatively narrow. Due to the AI&amp;rsquo;s being narrow it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to be literate in the many models that are available and what they excel at vs what they are just ok at vs what they cannot do at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Sharpstone.blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome-to-sharpstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome-to-sharpstone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-sharpstoneblog&#34;&gt;Welcome to Sharpstone.blog&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/arrowhead-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sharpstone Arrowhead Logo&#34; title=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to &lt;em&gt;Sharpstone.blog&lt;/em&gt;! I’m Randy Haas, an IT professional with almost three decades of experience spanning the full spectrum of technology—from infrastructure to development, information security, and leadership. This site is my platform to share insights, trends, and practical advice at the intersection of technology, leadership, finance, and accounting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-journey&#34;&gt;My Journey&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My career began in the trenches of IT infrastructure: designing networks, configuring switches and firewalls, building servers, managing databases, and planning data centers. Over time, I expanded into software development and information security consulting, honing a deep understanding of how systems—and the people who run them—work together. In recent years, I’ve led teams implementing and optimizing enterprise platforms like ServiceNow and Salesforce, blending technical expertise with strategic leadership.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it thinking? Artificial Intelligence: A Guide for Thinking Humans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/is-it-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/is-it-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/is-it-thinking.png&#34; alt=&#34;Is it thinking&#34; title=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I recommend reading &amp;quot;Artificial Intelligence: A Guide for Thinking&#xA;Humans&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I just finished up &amp;quot;Artificial Intelligence: A Guide for Thinking&#xA;Humans&amp;quot; by Melanie Mitchell. It was a great, quick read. I recommend it&#xA;to anyone that wants a great primer on AI with or without a background&#xA;in tech. Mitchell does an excellent job making complex topics&#xA;approachable and sharing metaphors and examples that make AI&#39;s nuances&#xA;understandable for non-specialists. Dr. Mitchell manages to explore the&#xA;topics to a certain depth without drowning you in tech speak.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Intelligence and Leadership</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/eq_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/eq_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/EQarticle.png&#34; alt=&#34;Emotional Intelligence and Leadership&#34; title=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the great buzzwords of the last several years has been EQ, or&#xA;emotional intelligence.  John Maxwell ranks this as the most important&#xA;form of intelligence because it is behind our ability to connect with&#xA;others.  In this time of social distancing, unrest, injustice, and&#xA;uncertainty about the future connecting with others is the most&#xA;important thing we can be doing.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IT professionals, in particular, can reap benefits from focusing their&#xA;#leadership and their teams on raising their emotional&#xA;intelligence. Zoom and Webex meetings take away some of the personal&#xA;touch, as our interactions tend to be hyper-focused and lose the nuances&#xA;gained by a handful of interpersonal meetings during a typical&#xA;workday. These nuances can be the difference between cohesiveness and a&#xA;functionally competent but unengaged team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
